Robert S. McNamara Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
While writing his memoir In Retrospect, McNamara offered a proposal to initiate a joint American-Vietnamese project on the Vietnam War based on the principles of critical oral history and modeled after the Cuban Missile Crisis Project. Principally organized by James G. Blight of Brown University, and sponsored by Brown's Thomas J. Watson, Jr. Institute for International Studies, the project consisted of many preliminary meetings and full conferences from 1995 to 1999 that convened under the general title “Missed Opportunities: Revisiting the Decisions of the Vietnam War.” McNamara's exploratory trip to Hanoi in November 1995 on behalf of the project, his first trip to Vietnam since the 1960s, generated considerable domestic controversy and subsequent criticism. Material in Part II of the Subject File documents all aspects of the project whose data provided the basis for McNamara's book Argument without End.
Many of the same subjects and topics explored in Part I of the Subject File are continued in Part II, including files on arms control and nuclear weapons, commissions, conferences and meetings, geopolitical issues, and onchocerciasis (river blindness). Upon his departure from the Defense Department, McNamara was presented with a multivolume bound compilation of his background briefings and public statements. These volumes along with several files of declassified memoranda, position papers, and reports and other related material provide further insights to McNamara's years as defense secretary.
In 1995, McNamara, in collaboration with Brian VanDeMark, published In Retrospect. Described in the preface as “... the book I planned never to publish,” McNamara proceeded to set forth his account and analysis of the Vietnam War with emphasis on the mistakes made and lessons learned from America's involvement in the conflict. The Speeches and Writings series contains extensive research files, drafts, editing and production material, public response and reaction, interview transcripts, promotion and publicity material, and related items concerning the writing and publication of McNamara's long-awaited memoir.
Planned as a sequel to his Vietnam memoir and originally drafted as “In Retrospect II,” McNamara published Argument without End in 1999. Based on conversations between Americans and Vietnamese who were active participants during the war, the book, cowritten with James G. Blight and Robert K. Brigham, was the product of the Vietnam War Project described above. Proposals and outlines for the book are contained in the Speeches and Writings series, in addition to correspondence, editing, publicity and publication material, and drafts from various stages of the book's progress. These files, along with those for the Vietnam War Project, provide an extensive record of the project and the book that grew from it.
In Wilson's Ghost, James G. Blight and McNamara collaborated again to publish an analysis of American foreign policy in the post-Cold War world. The Speeches and Writings series documents the research and publication of McNamara's last major book, including correspondence exchanged with Blight, drafts, and editing and publicity material.
Other subjects and topics featured in Speeches and Writings include the documentary film The Fog of War; Deborah Shapley's biography, Promise and Power; and continuing files from Part I concerning interviews, printed and typescript copies of public statements, and radio and television appearances. The Fog of War, winner of the Academy Award for documentary feature in 2003, was produced and directed by Errol Morris and consists of interviews with McNamara and archival footage. The film considers McNamara's personal and public life and examines the eleven lessons of war posited in his memoir In Retrospect. Speeches and Writings contains reaction to and commentary on the film as well as correspondence, interview transcripts, and research material from the film's production. Files on Promise and Power, include transcripts from a set of interviews conducted by Shapley with McNamara in preparation for the book that complement related files in Part I.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in two parts, seventeen series within:
Part I:
Correspondence, 1964-1996
World Bank, 1958-1997
Organizations, 1968-2002
Subject File, 1960-2003
Speeches and Writings, 1961-2000
Miscellany, 1965-1998
Classified, 1968-1992
Oversize, 1973-1974
Part II:
World Bank, 1967-2005
Organizations, 1969-2006
Subject File, 1946-2006
Speeches and Writings, 1934-2006
Miscellany, 1960-2009
Classified, 1962-2002
Top Secret, 1963-1967, 2000
Sensitive Compartmented Information, 1962
Oversize, 1994
Container List
- Part I: Correspondence, 1964-1996 (Box I:1-20)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, memoranda, notes, cards, and letters exchanged between correspondents other than McNamara, as well as enclosures containing speeches, printed matter, reports, typescripts, transcripts, and other miscellaneous attachments.
  Organized in an alphabetical file arranged by name of correspondent. A small chronological file concludes the series.
  - Alphabetical file (Box I:1)
    - Adler, Mortimer Jerome, 1982, 1992
    - Allison, Graham T., 1982-1988, 1995
    - Alsop, Joseph and Susan Mary, 1980-1985
    - Anderson, Robert O., 1969-1974, 1983
    - Aspin, Les, 1984-1992
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1972-1995, (3 folders)
    - Barr, Joseph W., 1970-1977
    - Bartlett, Charles, 1968, 1977-1978
    - Beatrix, Queen of the Netherlands, 1982-1989
    - Berelson, Bernard R., 1973-1978
    - Bergsten, C. Fred, 1986-1990
    - Blight, James G.
      - 1985
      - 1986-1995, (3 folders) (Box I:2)
    - Bogdan, N. A., 1968-1981
    - Botero, Rodrigo, 1970-1972, 1984
    - Braden, Joan, and family, 1984-1988, 1994
    - Braden, Susan, 1981-1988
    - Brandt, Willy, 1981-1987
    - Brokaw, Tom, 1982-1983, 1991
    - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1976-1978, 1985
    - Bundy, McGeorge, 1969-1993
    - Bundy, William P.
      - 1982
      - 1983-1985, 1994 (Box I:3)
    - Bush, George, 1988
    - “B” miscellaneous, 1981-1996, (4 folders)
    - Cabot, Louis, 1979-1981, 1990
    - Cabot, Thomas D., 1968-1986, 1993-1995
    - Christopher, Warren, 1992-1993
    - Clark, William, 1974-1985
    - Clausen, A. W., 1977-1985
    - Cleveland, Harlan and Lois B., 1992-1994
    - Cohen, Myer, 1973-1981
    - Colby, William E., 1978-1979 (Box I:4)
    - Conable, Barber B., 1984-1988
    - Connally, John B., 1975, 1986-1989
    - Crown, Lester, 1986-1994
    - Cutler, Lloyd N., 1974-1975, 1981-1982, 1988-1991
    - “C” miscellaneous, 1975, 1981-1996, (3 folders)
    - “D” miscellaneous
      - 1972-1984, (2 folders)
      - 1985-1996, (4 folders) (Box I:5)
    - Eddy, Edward D. and Polly, 1972-1983, 1992
    - Eggert, Robert J., 1967-1981, 1987-1989
    - Eiseman, Ben, 1981-1985, 1994-1995
    - Enthoven, Alain C., 1969, 1977-1996
    - Evans, Harold, 1984-1986
    - “E” miscellaneous, 1973-1995, (2 folders)
    - Fitt, Alfred B., 1968-1976 (Box I:6)
    - Freeman, Jane and Orville L., 1968, 1975-1989, (2 folders)
    - Fritchey, Polly, 1986-1991
    - “F” miscellaneous, 1968-1996, (2 folders)
    - Garwin, Richard L., 1984-1985
    - Gilpatric, Madelin and Roswell L., 1979-1994
    - Ginsburg, David, 1974, 1985-1995
    - Goodin, Marion and Vernon L., 1981-1985, 1991
    - Goodwin, Willard E., 1976-1988, 1994-1995
    - Gottfried, Kurt
      - 1985-1986
      - 1987-1992 (Box I:7)
    - Goulding, Philip G., 1981-1986, 1995
    - Graham, Donald E., 1985-1987
    - Graham, Katharine, 1995
    - “G” miscellaneous, 1968-1996, (3 folders)
    - Haas, Evelyn and Walter A., 1981-1996
    - Hamburg, David A., 1985-1993
    - Harriman, Pamela Digby Churchill Hayward and W. Averell, 1983-1989
    - Hendrickson, Paul, 1983-1987, 1994-1996
    - Houghton, Amory, 1982-1991
    - Houston, Charles S., 1982-1992 (Box I:8)
    - “H” miscellaneous, 1967, 1981-1995, (2 folders)
    - Ignatius, Paul R., 1968-1972, 1988-1989
    - “I” miscellaneous, 1968-1995
    - Javits, Jacob K., 1970-1983
    - Johnson, Lady Bird, 1974, 1981
    - Johnson, U. Alexis, 1968-1972 See also Classified
    - Jordan, Vernon, 1992-1993
    - “J” miscellaneous, 1970-1995, (2 folders)
    - Katzenbach, Lydia and Nicholas, 1986-1992
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1982-1988 (Box I:9)
    - Kochman, M. Nassim, 1982, 1993-1994
    - Kunin, Madeleine M., 1986-1991
    - “K” miscellaneous, 1982-1996, (2 folders)
    - Lee, John Marshall, 1983-1991
    - Livingston, Robert B., 1981-1993
    - Ljungh, Anders, 1977-1985, 1992
    - Loudon, John H., 1972-1990
    - Lown, Bernard, 1986, 1993-1994
    - Lurvink, Frans M. J., 1986-1991, (2 folders) (Box I:10)
    - “L” miscellaneous, 1982-1995, (3 folders)
    - Menell, Clive and Irene, 1982-1994, (3 folders)
    - Miller, Arjay, 1986-1992 (Box I:11)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1983-1992
    - Muller, Mervin, 1981-1985
    - “M” miscellaneous
      - 1968-1990, (7 folders)
      - 1991-1996, (2 folders) (Box I:12)
    - Nichols, Thomas S., 1969, 1975-1979
    - Nitze, Paul H., 1977-1985, 1994
    - Nunn, Sam, 1984-1988
    - Nye, Joseph S., 1987-1990
    - “N” miscellaneous, 1970-1995, (4 folders)
    - Okita, Saburo, 1981-1982, 1990-1993 (Box I:13)
    - Olds, Glenn A., 1967-1981
    - Owen, Henry, 1976-1983
    - “O” miscellaneous, 1970-1995, (3 folders)
    - “P” miscellaneous
      - 1969-1972, 1982-1990, (3 folders)
      - 1991-1996 (Box I:14)
    - “Q” miscellaneous, 1973, 1980-1993
    - Remington, Gailen, 1983-1984
    - Richardson, Elliot L., 1984-1992
    - Robinson, Charles W., 1972-1978 See also Classified
    - Rockefeller, David, 1969, 1975-1980, 1992
    - Rockefeller, John D. (1906-1978), 1967-1975
    - Rosenstein-Rodan, Paul N., 1968-1977
    - Rusk, Dean, 1983-1988
    - “R” miscellaneous, 1968-1996, (2 folders)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1917-2007), 1968-1971, 1984-1990
    - Schmidt, Helmut, 1984-1994 (Box I:15)
    - Sheinbaum, Stanley K., 1991-1993
    - Shriver, Eunice and Sargent, and family, 1985-1994
    - Smith, Gerard C., 1984-1994
    - Spivak, Lawrence E., 1968-1974
    - Strong, Maurice F., 1984-1992
    - “S” miscellaneous
      - 1968-1972, 1981-1988 See also Classified, (4 folders)
      - 1989-1996, (3 folders) (Box I:16)
    - Talbott, Strobe, 1987, 1996
    - Taylor, Carl E., 1975-1983
    - Taylor, Maxwell D., and family, 1975, 1987-1988
    - Thelen, Max, Jr., 1975, 1982, 1990-1994
    - Tidemand, Otto Grieg, 1968-1972, 1986-1987
    - Tydings, Joseph D., 1969-1975, 1981-1982
    - “T” miscellaneous
      - 1968-1976
      - 1977-1996, (5 folders) (Box I:17)
    - Udall, Stewart L., 1969-1973, 1984-1985
    - Urquhart, Brian, 1990
    - Ury, William L., 1984-1988
    - “U” miscellaneous, 1971-1995
    - Vail, Thomas, 1969-1974, 1984
    - Valenti, Jack, 1981-1983
    - Vance, Cyrus R., 1977-1991 See also Classified (Box I:18)
    - Vernon, Raymond, 1973-1981
    - “V” miscellaneous, 1969-1995, (2 folders)
    - Wachtmeister, Wilhelm, 1985-1990
    - Wales, Jane, 1988-1995
    - Ward, Barbara, 1968-1978
    - Warnke, Paul C., 1977, 1984-1988
    - Winship, Elizabeth and Thomas, 1980-1997
    - Wisner, Frank, 1992-1994
    - “W” miscellaneous
      - 1968-1971, 1980-1985, (2 folders)
      - 1986-1996, (4 folders) (Box I:19)
    - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1970, 1982-1983, 1993
    - Yankelevich, Efrem, 1985
    - York, Herbert F., 1982-1988
    - Young, Andrew, 1981-1983
    - “Y” miscellaneous, 1969-1994
    - Zeidenstein, George, 1976, 1981-1983, 1992
    - Zorza, Victor, 1978-1982 (Box I:20)
    - Zuckerman, Solly Zuckerman, Baron, 1970-1973, 1982-1986, 1993
    - Zuckert, Eugene M., 1968-1975, 1982, 1988, 1994
    - Zumwalt, Elmo R., 1973-1980
    - “Z” miscellaneous, 1970-1994
  - Chronological file, 1964, 1974-1985, (5 folders)
- Part I: World Bank, 1958-1997 (Box I:20-38)
  Correspondence, memoranda, cables, interviews, reports and studies, policy and research papers, notes and notebooks, drafts and typescripts, agenda and records of meetings, financial and legal records, statements, speeches and writings, press releases, photographs, printed matter, and miscellaneous material relating to the operations and policies of the World Bank.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject, topic, or type of material.
  - Agriculture, 1976 (Box I:20)
  - Assignments, lists of projects, and policy papers, 1969-1973
  - Bennett, William, memoranda of McNamara trips, 1968-1978, (2 folders) (Box I:21)
  - Bond market
    - Background material, 1976-1980
    - Intermediate term U.S. market, 1969-1970
  - Capital
    - Background material, 1958, 1969
    - Financial policy, 1975
    - Market analysis, 1975
    - Subscriptions and voting representation, 1972-1975 (Box I:22)
  - Commentary about bank
    - Clark, William, 1971-1975
    - General, 1968-1975
    - Staff, 1971-1975
  - Committees
    - Board of governors, 1970-1971
    - Development
      - 1974-1975, Jan. See also Classified, (3 folders)
      - 1975, Feb.-1977, (3 folders) (Box I:23)
    - Program planning and budgeting, 1977
    - Quality of bank lending, 1976-1977
    - Reorganization, 1987
  - Commodities, 1975
  - Conferences and meetings
    - Annual meetings
      - 1970, Copenhagen, Denmark See also Classified
      - 1973, Nairobi, Kenya
        - African caucus
        - Press clippings
    - Bilderberg meetings, 1975 (Box I:24)
    - International Meeting on Development Policy, Heidelberg, Germany, (June 1970), 1968-1970, (2 folders)
    - Reunión Internacional sobre Cooperación y Desarrollo (Cancún Summit), Cancún, Mexico, 1981
    - Tidewater meetings, 1968-1980, (3 folders)
    - World Food Conference, Rome, Italy (Nov. 1974), 1974-1975
  - Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research, 1970-1974
  - Correspondence
    - 1971-1976 See also Classified
    - 1977, 1983-1988, 1995 (Box I:25)
  - Country file
    - Chile, 1972-1974, (2 folders)
    - China, 1971-1979, (2 folders)
    - India
      - Food production, 1974-1975
      - Newspaper clippings, 1976
      - Water rights, 1976
    - Indochina, 1972-1973 (Box I:26)
    - Iran, 1972
    - Miscellany and notes, 1970-1979
    - Pakistan, 1971
  - Departments
    - Economics, 1968-1971
    - Operations evaluation, 1975-1976
    - Programming and budgeting
      - Correspondence, 1971-1973
      - Lending programs, 1975-1976
      - Portfolio analysis, 1975
    - Transportation, 1972
  - Economic development (Box I:27)
    - Background material, 1969-1970, (2 folders)
    - Policy analysis, 1969-1972
  - Education, 1968-1970
  - Energy and oil policy, 1974-1975, (2 folders)
  - Export-Import Bank of the United States
    - Brazil steel project, 1971
    - General, 1971
  - Fiftieth anniversary, history of the bank project, 1992
  - Financial and operating statements, 1970-1973
  - Five-year plans (Box I:28)
    - General, 1977-1979
    - Underwriter memoranda, 1972
  - Food production
    - Nutrition, 1973
    - Projections, 1975
    - World food policy, 1975
  - Human rights, 1977
  - IMEDE Management Development Institute, 1980
  - Inflation, 1974
  - International Development Association
    - Policies, 1968-1977, (2 folders)
    - Replenishments
      - Third, 1969-1972
      - Fourth, 1972-1974
      - Fifth, 1975-1977, (2 folders) (Box I:29)
  - International Monetary Fund
    - General, 1974-1979
    - Interim Committee of the Board of Directors, 1975
  - Interviews
    - Alphabetical file, 1975-1980, (3 folders)
    - Background material, 1961-1965, 1980-1981 (Box I:30)
    - Meet the Press, briefing book, 1974
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1982
    - Silk, Leonard, 1978-1981
  - Investments
    - Institutional appeals, 1968-1972
    - Private foreign investment, 1968-1972
    - Third window loans, 1975
  - Mekong Basin Dam Project, 1969-1970 See also Classified
  - Miscellany, 1971-1982
  - Notes and notebooks (Box I:31)
    - Conversations, 1968-1972, (2 folders)
    - Field visits, 1968-1981 See also Container I:35, Robert S. McNamara collection, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977
  - Office of the President of the World Bank
    - Second-term election, 1971-1972
    - Third-term election, 1976-1977 See also Classified
  - Organization study, 1971-1972, (2 folders)
  - Personnel (Box I:32)
    - Appointment of bank officers, 1975-1977
    - Morale reports, 1971-1976
    - Pension benefits, 1974-1977
    - Ripmar, Hugh B., Forthway Center for Advanced Studies, 1970
    - Secretarial, typing, and clerical staff, petitions of grievances, 1971
  - Photographs, 1968-1977, undated, (8 folders)
  - Policy planning
    - Basic needs program, 1977-1978
    - Global targets for development cooperation, 1977 (Box I:33)
  - Population, 1968-1977, (3 folders)
  - Press clippings
    - 1969-1976, Sept., (4 folders)
    - 1976, Oct.-1981 (Box I:34)
  - Reports and studies
    - Mason, Edward S., “The World Bank Group and Private Enterprise,” 1975
    - Miscellaneous 1968-1977 See also Classified
  - Retirement
    - Farewell letters
      - Drafts and recipient lists, 1981
      - Responses, 1980-1981
    - Miscellany, 1980-1981
    - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1981, (1 folder) (Box I:35)
    - Pension benefits program, 1983-1987
  - Robert S. McNamara collection (Joint Bank-Fund Library), indexes to series, 1968-1981 See also Container I:31, Field visits, (3 folders)
  - Robert S. McNamara Fellowships Program, 1984, 1997 (Box I:36)
  - Rowen, Hobart, 1975, 1985
  - Rural development
    - General, 1975
    - Nairobi, Kenya, speech, implementation and objectives, 1973-1974
  - Sommers, David, 1970-1973
  - Speeches and writings
    - By McNamara
      - Addresses to the Board of Governors, 1973-1980, (2 folders)
      - Concluding remarks at annual meetings, 1968-1980
      - Miscellaneous addresses and statements, 1968-1981
      - United Nations Economic and Social Council, 1968-1974, (2 folders)
    - By others (Box I:37)
      - Miscellaneous, 1967-1975, 1981-1982, (2 folders)
      - Snow, C. P., “The State of Siege,” 1967-1968
  - Technical notes
    - Employment, industrialization, and urbanization, 1969-1970
    - Financial analysis, 1976
      - Nos. 1-19, (3 folders)
      - Nos. 20-22 (Box I:38)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968
  - Trade and tariffs, 1969-1972
  - United Nations
    - Seventh Special Session, 1975
    - United Nations Environment Programme, 1974
  - United States
    - Bond issue pricing, 1976
    - Enke report on U.S. development policy, 1973
    - Government attitude toward World Bank, 1971-1974 See also Classified
  - Urban poverty, 1975
- Part I: Organizations, 1968-2002 (Box I:38-77)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports and studies, policy and research papers, organizational records, notes, drafts and typescripts, agenda and records of meetings, transcripts, project proposals, briefing books, financial records, statements, speeches and writings, working papers, itineraries, press releases, photographs, printed matter, and miscellaneous material concerning McNamara's service as a member on the boards and advisory councils of various private corporations and nongovernmental institutions.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization.
  - Africa Leadership Forum, meeting, “The Leadership Challenge of Economic Reforms in Africa,” Washington, D.C., 1989 (Box I:38)
  - African Development Bank
    - Committee of Nine, meetings, Abidjan, Ivory Coast
      - 1988
        - Feb. 10-11
        - June 4-5, (1 folder) (Box I:39)
      - 1989, Jan. 30-31
    - Committee of Ten, meeting, London, England, 1989
    - Correspondence, 1987-1994, (2 folders)
    - Meetings
      - 1991, July 8-9, North-South Roundtable on African Debt Relief, Recovery, and Democracy, Abidjan, Ivory Coast, 1988-1991
      - 1993, May 11, “HIV/AIDS and Development in Africa,” Abidjan, Ivory Coast, 1991-1993
    - Miscellany, 1981, 1994 (Box I:40)
  - Albert Einstein Peace Prize Foundation, 1982-1988, 1994
  - Alexander S. Onassis Public Benefit Foundation, 1982-1987, (3 folders)
  - American Assembly
    - General, 1989-1993
    - Joint workshop with the Japan Center for International Exchange, Tokyo, Japan, 1989
  - American Philosophical Society, 1981-1987
  - American Soviet Youth Orchestra, 1989-1990
  - Arms Control Association, 1998
  - Arthur F. Burns Fellowship Program, 1990-1994 (Box I:41)
  - Aspen Institute
    - Award dinner, 1989
    - Conferences and meetings
      - 1983, July 30-Aug. 11, “China: Past, Present, and Future,” Crestone, Colo.
      - 1984, Nov. 6-11, “Modernization in the People's Republic of China and Its Impact on the World Community,” Beijing, China, (2 folders)
      - 1986, May 5-6, “Modernization in the People's Republic of China,” Wye Plantation, Queenstown, Md.
      - 1987, Board of Trustees, Wye Plantation, Queenstown, Md.
      - 1991, Aug. 17-22, “The United States and the World Economy,” Aspen, Colo.
        - Background material and notes, 1991
        - Briefing book, 1991 (Box I:42)
      - 1992, Aug. 26-30, “The United States and the World Economy,” Strasbourg, France
      - 1993, Aug. 21-26, “The Future of the World Economy,” Aspen, Colo.
        - Background material and notes, 1991-1993
        - Briefing book, 1993 (Box I:43)
      - 1994
        - Aug. 12-14, Aspen Institute Distinguished Fellows, Aspen, Colo.
          - Drafts and working papers, 1994
          - General, 1994
        - Aug. 28-Sept. 1, “Future of the World Economy,” Tokyo, Japan
      - 1998
        - Apr. 24-26, Board of Trustees, Wye Plantation, Queenstown, Md.
        - Aug. 19-22, “Change and Prosperity,” Aspen, Colo.
  - Atlantic Council of the United States
    - General
      - 1974-1983
      - 1984-1999, (3 folders) (Box I:44)
    - Meeting, Beijing Institute for International Strategic Studies, Beijing, China (Oct. 1990), 1987-1990
    - Working groups
      - Arms control and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1981-1984
      - Military service, 1981-1982
      - U.S. relations with Cuba, 1994
  - Battelle Memorial Trust, meetings (Box I:45)
    - 1994, July 26-29, International Advisory Board meeting, Richland, Wash.
    - 1995, Jan. 9-13, “Global Climate Change and the Social Sciences,” International Advisory Board meeting, Seoul, Korea
      - Background material, 1992-1995
      - General, 1994-1995
    - 1998, Oct. 15-16, “A Global Energy Technology Strategy,” Washington D.C.
      - Background material, 1997-1998, (2 folders)
      - Briefing book, 1998
      - General, 1998 (Box I:46)
    - 1999, June 29, “Global Climate Change,” Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, Washington D.C.
  - Bretton Woods Committee, 1984-1995, (3 folders)
  - Brookings Institution
    - Conferences and meetings
      - 1986, Nov. 6, Board of Trustees, Washington, D.C.
      - 1987
        - Mar. 9, “Colloquium on Nuclear Operations and Command and Control,” Washington, D.C., 1986-1987
        - Apr. 30-May 1, Board of Trustees, Annapolis, Md.
      - 1998, June 25-27, Trans-Atlantic Economic Dialogue Conference, Lansdowne, Va., 1997-1998
      - 2000, Jan. 13-14, “Policy and the Presidency 2000,” Brookings Council Retreat, Washington, D.C.
    - General, 1982, 1997-2002 (Box I:47)
    - Lardy, Nicholas R., “China's Unfinished Economic Revolution,” discussion group, 1997
  - Business Executives for National Security, 1991-1993
  - California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, Calif., 1976, 1989-1990
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
    - General, 1988, 1994
    - Meeting, “Non-proliferation and Arms Control after the Cold War,” Washington, D.C., 1994
  - Center for the Study of Soviet Change, 1992
  - Council on Economic Priorities, 1990
  - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Correspondence
      - 1968, 1982-1988
      - 1989-1997 (Box I:48)
    - European-American Project Advisory Group, 1983-1984